Itamar Franco Salazar Reque

🖈 itamarsalazar.netlify.app | 🖸 itamarsalazar | 🖫 Itamar | 🛅 itamarsalazar

Summary_

Currently working at the Medical Image Laboratory (LIM) from PUCP exploring robust methods for ultrasound image formation with deep learning. Former researcher in the group of Signal Processing and Artificial Intelligence at INICTEL-UNI where we applied machine learning and signal & image processing techniques in agricultural and biomedical projects.

Former intern in the Signal Processing Laboratory (LTS4) at EPFL studying the inductive bias of deep neural networks (DNN) using concepts from signals and systems. I have teaching experience in signal processing and AI-related courses. During my master, I studied the inverse problem for electroencephalographic signals and for my undergrad thesis I explored machine learning algorithms to automatically detect diseased areas on plant leaves.

My current interest are the application of DNN for ultrasound image formation and the study of its robustness.

Education

Pontificia Universidad Catolica del Peru

Lima, Perú

PHD, ENGINEERING (ONGOING)

- · Exploring robust methods for ultrasound image reconstruction using deep learning with the supervision of Roberto Lavarello.
- With scholarship from peruvian government

Universidad Nacional de Ingenieria

Lima, Perú

MASTER OF SCIENCE, ELECTRONIC ENGINEER

- Research on the performance of EEG inverse techniques when varying electrode numbers and noise
- Under the supervision of Carlos Mugruza
- · With scholarship from peruvian government

Universidad Nacional de Ingenieria

Lima, Perú

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

• Placed first in graduating class

Experience ____

PLICP Lima, Peru

Aug., 2022 - Present **TEACHER ASSISTANT**

· Digital Signal Processing

RESEARCH INTERN

Universities

LECTURER

INICTEL-UNI Lima, Perú

SPECIALIZED RESEARCHER IN TECHNOLOGICAL DEVELOPMENT, COLLABORATOR

2018 - 2022

Lima, Perú

March, 2019 - 2022

Oct., 2020 - March, 2021

- Avocado tree analysis using images acquired via drones. [Code][About the project]
- Amplifying the small movements a person makes when breathing.[Code] [About the project]
- App to automatically identify avocado diseases from digital images. [About the project]
- Satellite image processing to calculate evapotranspiration. [About the project]]

EPFL Lausanne, Switzerland

· Studying the inductive bias of Deep Neural Networks under the direction of Pascal Frossard

· With scholarship from the peruvian government.

• Signals and Systems - Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas: 04/2020 - 03/2022

Multilayer Perceptrons and introduction to Fuzzy Logic - Universidad Tecnológica del Perú: 06/2019-03/2020

Signals and Systems - Universidad Nacional Tecnológica de Lima Sur: 03/2019 - 06/2019

NYIT New York, U.S.A VISITING RESEARCH FELLOW Oct., 2017 - Dec., 2017

· Studying CPA algorithm and methods to process functional imaging of olfactory bulb responses

• Under the direction of Gonzalo Otazu.

PERU MENU Lima, Peru

DEVELOPER July, 2012 - Sept., 2012

• An app to find restaurants near to you.

ITAMAR FRANCO SALAZAR REQUE · CV

Teaching to best students

July, 2010 - Sept., 2010

• Teaching arithmetic to top-10 students from first secondary year.

Contributions_

Salazar-Reque, I.F., Lavarello, R., "Robustness of an ultrasound deep beamformer to low-energy input [1] Unpublished perturbations in worst-case performance", 2022 Salazar-Reque, I.F., D. Arteaga, K. G. Huamán and S. Huamán Bustamante, "A CNN-based algorithm for selecting tree-of-interest images acquired by UAV," 2021 IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning [2] Conference and Applied Network Technologies (ICMLANT), 2021, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1109/ICMLANT53170.2021.9690556. Ortiz-Jimenez, G., Salazar-Reque, I.F., Apostolos Modas, Seyed-Mohsen Moosavi-Dezfooli, Pascal Frossard. [3] A neural anisotropic view of underspecification in deep learning. In: Robust and Reliable Machine Learning Workshop in the Real World Workshop at International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021) Salazar-Reque, I.F., Otazu G., Huaman S. (2020) Replacing FC layers in a CNN could improve robustness [4] Poster against adversarial attacks. CIFAR DLRL Summer School (available under request) Salazar-Reque, I.F., Huaman, S. Automatic Leaf Segmentation from Images Taken Under Uncontrolled Conditions Using Convolutional Neural Networks. In: Brazilian Technology Symposium'19 – Perú 2019 [5] Conference (BTSym 2019), **DOI:** 10.1007/978-3-030-57566-3_27 Morales, G., Salazar-Reque, I.F., Telles, J., Díaz, D. Detecting Violent Robberies in CCTV Videos Using Deep [6] Learning. In: 15th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence Applications and Innovations (AIAI 2019), Conference **DOI:** 10.1007/978-3-030-19826-7 Salazar-Reque, I.F., Pacheco, A.G., Rodriguez, R.Y., Lezama, J., and Huaman, S. An image processing [7] method to automatically identify Avocado leaf state. In: XXII Symposium on Image, Signal Processing and Conference Artificial Vision (STSIVA 2019). DOI: 10.1109/STSIVA.2019.8730218 Salazar-Reque, I.F., Kemper G., Huamán S. G. H., Telles J. and Diaz D., (2019). An Algorithm for Plant Disease [8] Visual Symptom Detection in Digital Images based on Superpixels. International Journal on Advanced Journal Science, Engineering and Information Technology, 9(1), pp. 194-203, **DOI:** 10.18517/ijaseit.9.1.5322

Skills_

Programming Python, MATLAB. Legacy: C++, Qt, Java, HTML

DL Frameworks PyTorch, Keras, TensorFlow

Languages English (100/120 - TOEFL iBT), French (basic), Spanish (mother tongue)

Certifications Huawei Artificial Intelligence (HCIA-AI). [See certificate]

Miscellaneous Photography (Bird photography), Guitar

Awards_

2022	Scholarship, fully funded doctoral studies	Lima, Perú
2020	Scholarship, internship at EPFL	Lima, Perú
2017	Scholarship, fully funded master studies	Lima, Perú
2015	First place, undergraduate class	Lima, Perú

Volunteering Activities _____

Organizer, Machine Learning reading group [Link]	Virtual	
Advisor, Journal Club IA UNI	Lima, Perú	
Volunteer , IEEE UNI Student Branch	Lima, Perú	
Chair, IEEE UNI Student Branch, we published some reports here: https://issuu.com/reieeeuni	Lima, Perú	
Vice Chair, Circuits and Systems IEEE UNI Student Chapter	Lima, Perú	
Volunteer , Rural Telecommunication Group	Lima, Perú	
Co-Founder , Computer Science Research Group - GICS Dennis Ritchie	Lima, Perú	
(https://es-la.facebook.com/GISCDennisRitchieUNI)	Liitia, Feru	
Organizer, Student Congress - IEEE INTEERCON UNI 2011.	Lima, Perú	
	Advisor, Journal Club IA UNI Volunteer, IEEE UNI Student Branch Chair, IEEE UNI Student Branch, we published some reports here: https://issuu.com/reieeeuni Vice Chair, Circuits and Systems IEEE UNI Student Chapter Volunteer, Rural Telecommunication Group Co-Founder, Computer Science Research Group - GICS Dennis Ritchie (https://es-la.facebook.com/GISCDennisRitchieUNI)	